Gordon Institute Records UA184
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Gordon Institute Records
1987 -- 1999
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Engineering
Gordon Institute
UA184
9.8 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Gordon Institute, 2018.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Publications; 2017 accessions; and 2018 accessions.
Biographical / Historical
In 1984, The Gordon Institute is founded by Dr. Bernard Gordon, founder of Analogic Corporation and NeuroLogica Corps. The Gordon Institute is one of the first educational institutions designed and developed specifically to create engineering leaders. From 1984 to 1987, The Institutes mission, curriculum, and policies are developed and the School prepares for accreditation by the New England Association of Schools and Colleges (NEASC). In 1987, The first class of seven students graduates from The Gordon Institute. In 1991, The NEASC accredits The Gordon Institute to confer the degree of Master of Science in Engineering Management. In 1992, The Gordon Institute merges with Tufts University. In 2001, Tufts Gordon Institute assumes responsibility for Tufts Entrepreneurial Leadership Program. In doing so, the Institute broadens its mission to encompass innovation and entrepreneurship as well as engineering leadership.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains pamphlets created by the Gordon Institute, as well as student records from before Tufts acquired the Gordon Institute of Wakefield, MA, and acquisitions files between Tufts and the Gordon Institute.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Centers and Institutes
- Publications, 1990 -- 1999; UA184.001; .185 Linear Feet 1 box
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains two copies of a Gordon Institute pamphlet.
  - Gordon Institute, Continuing Education for Engineering Management, circa 1990 -- 1999; UA184-001 (Box data_value_missing_11bc2dbb750c300ff9d1403ef7c99db5, Box 1)
- 2017 accessions, circa 1987 -- 1996; UA184.002; 9.6 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order. Student records are largely arranged alphabetically by last name.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by the Gordon Institute, 2017, accession UA-2018-037.
  This series contains student records from before Tufts acquired the Gordon Institute of Wakefield, MA; as well as acquisitions files between Tufts and the Gordon Institute, including reports to the NEASC, site visit information for the NEASC and the Board of Regents, and alumni files.
  - Addis, Robert, 1987 -- 1988; UA184.002.002.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - Appel, Richard, 1992 -- 1993; UA184.002.002.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Banaska, Kelly, 1990 -- 1992; UA184.002.002.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Blom, Eric, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.002.00004; 2 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Chiacchia, Robert, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.002.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Craig, Mary, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.002.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dyatlov, Vadim, 1992 -- 1992; UA184.002.002.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Evans, Steven, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.002.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fan, Hua, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.002.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Feld, Peter, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.002.00010; 3 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
  - Foster, Roy, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.002.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Gang, Lian, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.002.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Golden, Tim, 1992 -- 1993; UA184.002.003.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Greim, Michael, 1987 -- 1988; UA184.002.003.00002; 2 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Gusinov, Alex, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.003.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hahn, Gunter, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.003.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Harden-DeSantis, Maria, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.003.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hoang, Nhan, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.003.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hong, Jiang, circa 1994 -- 1994; UA184.002.003.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Jia, Chen, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.003.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jones, Mark, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.003.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Joy, William, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.003.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Kary, Mitch, 1987 -- 1988; UA184.002.003.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Katamura, Shuichi, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.003.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ke, Liu, 1987 -- 1988; UA184.002.003.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ladas, Christopher, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.004.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Li, Zhou, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.004.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Marcos, Gary, 1987 -- 1989; UA184.002.004.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Martin, Mark, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.004.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Mayer, Eliot, circa 1990 -- 1990; UA184.002.004.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - McKenney, Roland, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.004.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Michael, Manfred, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.004.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mondello, Jay, circa 1994 -- 1994; UA184.002.004.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Muller, Jeremy, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.004.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Muraki, Koichi, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.005.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Nakamura, Atsushi, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.005.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nguyen, Simon, 1992 -- 1993; UA184.002.005.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ni, Shouzhong, 1992 -- 1993; UA184.002.005.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Qun, Zhing, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.005.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rong, Han, circa 1988 -- 1988; UA184.002.005.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sawyer, John, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.005.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Schubnel, Jay, circa 1994 -- 1994; UA184.002.005.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Shippen, Peter, 1992 -- 1993; UA184.002.005.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Shuqun, Wang, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.005.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Suzuki, Kaoru, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.005.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Suzuki, Tatsuro, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.005.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tomizawa, Jun, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.005.00013; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Tong, Nie, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.005.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Unger, David, 1987 -- 1988; UA184.002.006.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Varanasi, Vijay, 1991 -- 1992; UA184.002.006.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Varner, Jon, circa 1990 -- 1990; UA184.002.006.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Whitmal, Nathaniel, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.006.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Williams, Stuart, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.006.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Winston, David, 1988 -- 1988; UA184.002.006.00006; 2 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Wirth, Axel, 1987 -- 1988; UA184.002.006.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Xu, Bo, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.006.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Xu, Gong, 1989 -- 1990; UA184.002.006.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Yong, Su, 1988 -- 1989; UA184.002.007.00001; 2 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Ziamin, Wang, 1990 -- 1991; UA184.002.007.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Klimovitsky, Vladimir, 1989 -- 1989; UA184.002.007.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln, Robert, 1994 -- 1999; UA184.002.007.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Long, Michael, circa 1987 -- 1994; UA184.002.007.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Long, Zhang Hua, 1989 -- 1989; UA184.002.007.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mohieddin, Hasan, 1993 -- 1993; UA184.002.007.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Satake, Nozomi, 1991 -- 1991; UA184.002.007.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Inactive Students, 1988 -- 1992; UA184.002.007.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Inactive Students, 1994 -- 1994; UA184.002.007.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Inactive Students, 1994 -- 1994; UA184.002.007.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Inactive Students, 1995 -- 1995; UA184.002.007.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Inactive Students, 1996 -- 1996; UA184.002.007.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Acquisition files: Alumni, Board of Regents, NEASC, circa 1987 -- 1992; UA184.002.008; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 8)
    20 years from the date of creation.
  - Acquisition files: NEASC reports, circa 1987 -- 1991; UA184.002.009; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_ca7b0ae87a6017d7c18f1d9246db9c02, Box 9)
- 2018 accessions, circa 1987 -- 1994; UA184.003; 5 Folder(s)
  This series is arranged in received order.
  Records containing information related to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
  This series contains transcripts and student records from before Tufts acquired the Gordon Institute of Wakefield, MA; and may include acquisitions files between Tufts and the Gordon Institute.
  Transferred by the Gordon Institute, 2018, accession UA-2018-046.
  - Transcripts for Wakefield-Gordon Institute, 1988 -- 1993; UA184.003.009.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_ca7b0ae87a6017d7c18f1d9246db9c02, Folder 2, Box 9)
    75 years from date of creation.
    Accessions
    UA-2018-046
  - Kaneko, Masaaki, circa 1987 -- 1994; UA184.003.009.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_ca7b0ae87a6017d7c18f1d9246db9c02, Folder 3, Box 9)
  - Flagg, Douglas, 1991; UA184.003.009.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_ca7b0ae87a6017d7c18f1d9246db9c02, Folder 4, Box 9)
  - Kitade, Takeshi, circa 1987 -- 1994; UA184.003.009.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_ca7b0ae87a6017d7c18f1d9246db9c02, Folder 5, Box 9)
  - Info - Telemetry, circa 1987 -- 1994; UA184.003.009.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_ca7b0ae87a6017d7c18f1d9246db9c02, Folder 6, Box 9)